Adrian Pistoleanu

Romanian, 30 years old, Male Telephone: 07589593187

E-mail: adrian.pistoleanu@outlook.com

Preston, Lancashire

Available for relocation(in nearby area)



Experienced Software Developer with over 8 years working in IT industry(and 4 years in .NET environment), specialising in Microsoft stack technologies, developing bespoke web and software solutions. Interest in working with the latest Microsoft technologies because i like their approach and philosophy of building business oriented platforms and also tools that make development faster.

Also, interested in Al/Machine Learning, The Internet of Things, Quantum computing, Augmented/Mixed Reality and many other technologies with huge growth potential.

SKILLS SUMMARY

Backend: C#, LINQ, ASP.NET MVC, Ajax, PowerShell

Frontend: WinForms, ASP.NET WebForms, HTML 5, CSS 3, LESS, SASS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Jquery, JSON, XML,

CMS(Umbraco and php based cms(Wordpress, Blogger, Joomla, Prestashop))

Very strong debugging and testing skills.

SDLC: Scrum, Agile, Continous integration and development

Testing: Manual testing, Black/white/greybox, Automatic(Nunit), Emulate database(Moq)

IDE: MS Visual Studio 2015, 2017, JetBrains Rider, Expression Web, Sublime

Database: Microsoft SQL Server 2016, SSMS, SSIS, SSRS

ORM: Entity Framework (Code first and Database first), LLBLGen Pro

Web Services: WCF(SOAP and REST), ASP.NET Web API(with REST, Swagger, OData, WebHook)

Source control: TFVC (Team Foundation Server), GIT

Project management: Microsoft Team Services, TFS, Trello, Jira, Slack Working following SOLID principles and the common design patterns.

Started working and improving in my private time on technologies like Azure, WPF(XAML, Windows Store apps) and Xamarin technologies.

EMPLOYMENT

Direct Validation Services – Preston, Lancashire (www.directgroup.co.uk)

April 2017 - March 2018

Role: Full stack .NET software developer

Direct Group provides insurance and claim solutions to some of the biggest companies of UK(like Amazon, Sainsburys, Lloyds Bank).

I was responsible for integrating insurance companies and suppliers in their bespoke WinForms desktop application (which is used by hundreds of claim hundreds) – this is a massive app, 10 years old, millions lines of code. Developed many modules for integrating Irish insurance companies and fulfilment houses in this app, performed massive changes to the core of this software (like new VAT rate, new Currencies). At the moment I'm responsible for all the new releases to production.

Technologies used: WinForms, C#, SQL Server(working with databases of millions of products, hundreds of tables), ASP.NET MVC, LINQ, Entity Framework, WCF, Web Services (created API system for live managing orders to suppliers), PowerShell, TFS.

SSRS (reports and also invoices), SSIS (packages for automatic loading the stock feeds daily).

Also worked on multiple web based applications for particular insurance companies (one example https://www.simplelandlordsinsurance.com/).

Developed components for insurance quote & buy journey and for a better customer experience.

Technologies used C#, ASP.NET MVC, SQL Server, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Angular.

Worked in an Agile development environment.

SC Mimir Software SRL, Ploiesti, Romania (www.mimir.ro)

September 2015 - March 2017

Role: Software Developer

Mimir Software is a company that provides website development, design, tailor-made software services, online advertising

I was responsible for the design & development of websites and some software tools(especially back end development)

- Technical lead in the development of a commercial .NET MVC web application (Azure cloud based, SAAS solution) that is about processing documents, extracting data from pdf documents (which is a very tough format to read) and converting them to office documents (word and excel) and sending some data to database using Entity Framework.
 - You can see this project at http://pdfparser.azurewebsites.net/This is a product to which i'll add many features and intend to commercialize it and make it one of the best in the market of document processing.
- Web Developer in many web projects for external clients, e-commerce websites, backend and frontend development (using frontend technologies like HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, many CMSs (asp.net and php based))
- Managed web servers (Linux and Windows) for hosting websites, allocating resources on the server
- Online advertising for our clients and their websites (using Adwords, Facebook, LinkedIn and others)
- Requirement gathering from clients and then designing and implementing the agreed scope of work (and also using that data in the agile development and testing)

June 2011 - August 2015

Freelancer on software and web projects

Working as a freelancer for multiple web projects using CMS and also building websites from scratch or bootstrap templates.

I've used web technologies like JQuery, PHP, many CMS platforms (Wordpress, Joomla, Prestashop, Blogger, WIX), ASP.NET

September 2012 – November 2014

INFO ACCRP SRL, Ploiesti, Ploiești, România

Network administrator, IT support – Part time job

ACCRP have courses for graduate students, unemployeds, workers in searching of a degree/license etc.

They have 3 computer labs each one with approximately 12 computers.

I've set up the network that covers all this labs and also 3 offices, set up the routers and other hardware network related, setting up the server (Linux and Windows Server), set up wi fi networks, printers, sharing hardware in the network, software install, configuring network on server and router for a strong security, installed network surveillance software.

I've also done pc maintenance and computer hardware modifications/configuration.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

2010 - 2012

Petroleum Gas University - Computer Science @ Master / Postuniversitary degree

, Ploiesti, Romania

Master's Degree -

Advanced technologies for information processing,

Computer Science,

Specialization Informatics Length: 4 semesters (2 years)

2006 - 2009

University of Bucharest - Computer Science @ Courses / Conferences , București, România Bachelor degree

2002 - 2006

Nichita Stanescu high school - Computer Science @ High School, Ploiești, România Mathematics - informatics department